Learn about removing an element in entity.
To remove the element 40 from an array.
First step, find 40.
The second step removed 40 from Andrei.
And the third step shift the rest of elements.
This is how we remove Element 40 from Andrei.
So the first step, if you if you're going to remove an element, we find the element.
Maybe the array is not containing this element, so we can't remove this.
The second step is removing the element, and the third step is shifting the rest of element because
we have an empty space.
Consider this array.
We have 10, 20, 30 and 40 and 50 at index.
First step is finding 40, so we are looking at 40 we have in the box for the iterator and searching
at 40 and we are searching for this.
Have a like an element 40.
OK, so we start comparing the elements, still finding the element at Index three.
So it's the fourth element at Index three containing 40.
So this is the element that we are going to remove.
This is the first step finding element 40.
The second step is removing 40.
We have removed 40.
The third step is shifting the rest of elements and removing the empty spaces.
This is the way how to remove an element from array.
Now consider removing an element in array.
This is the.
This is the ad that that the index and the algorithm, how it works.
This is the array and the coding from it to the left is how we remove an element in array.
So we have a for loop starting from equal to index at the index, where I need to remove that element.
And I less than size minus one and I plus plus so array at index I equal array index i +1.
This means that it will replace that for the next.
And that preceding and then next element with the current state.
This is how it works.
It will start and search for 40.
OK.
This is the iteration I three, I less than 40.
Yes.
So array at the three.
Equal array at four.
So if this were replaced, the Element Array Index, the three, this is the removing and switching
like replacing the element and index three with the element of index four.
OK.
And we remove that index by size.
My the last element.
The empty element with size minus minus.
And this is how we shrink that element in arrays.
The best case scenario is removing element at index.
Zero.
And the worst case is of an removing element at last.
And.